<clinical_study>
<study_id>
<org_name>
  BioMarinPharm
</org_name>
<org_full_name>
  BioMarin Pharmaceutical
</org_full_name>
<org_study_id>
  ASB-008
</org_study_id>
<nct_id>
  NCT00299000
</nct_id>
</study_id>
<is_fda_regulated>
  Yes
</is_fda_regulated>
<is_section_801>
  Yes
</is_section_801>
<delayed_posting>
  No
</delayed_posting>
<brief_title>
<textblock>
  A Phase 4 Two Dose Level Study of Naglazyme(TM) (Galsulfase) in Infants With MPS VI
</textblock>
</brief_title>
<official_title>
<textblock>
  A Phase 4 Multi-Center, Multi-National, Open-Label, Randomized, Two Dose Level Study of Naglazyme(TM) (Galsulfase) in Infants With Maroteaux-Lamy Syndrome (MPS VI)
</textblock>
</official_title>
<study_sponsor>
<lead_sponsor>
<agency>
  BioMarin Pharmaceutical
</agency>
</lead_sponsor>
</study_sponsor>
<resp_party>
<name_title>
  Emil D. Kakkis, MD, PhD.
</name_title>
<organization>
  BioMarin Pharmaceutical Inc.
</organization>
</resp_party>
<oversight_info>
<regulatory_authority>
  United States: Food and Drug Administration
</regulatory_authority>
<has_dmc>
  No
</has_dmc>
</oversight_info>
<brief_summary>
<textblock>
  The purpose of the study is to evaluate the safety and efficacy of two dose levels of Naglazyme in infants under the age of one year who have MPS VI by monitoring physical appearance, x-ray of the skeletal system and growth.
</textblock>
</brief_summary>
<detailed_descr>
<textblock>
  The primary objective of the study is to evaluate the efficacy of two dose levels of Naglazyme in preventing the progression of skeletal dysplasia in infants under the age of one year who have MPS VI by monitoring physical appearance, x-ray of the skeletal system and growth.
  The secondary objective of the study is to evaluate the efficacy of the two dose levels of Naglazyme in preventing several measures of disease progression in infants under the age of one year who have MPS VI by monitoring urinary GAGs, gross and fine motor function, cardiac function, vision, hearing, and use of health resources.
  The safety objective of the study is to evaluate the safety of two dose levels of Naglazyme in infants under the age of one year who have MPS VI.
</textblock>
</detailed_descr>
<status_block>
<status>
 Active, not recruiting 
</status>
<date>
2009-05 
</date>
</status_block>
<start_date>
<date>
  2007-09
</date>
</start_date>
<last_follow_up_date
 type="Anticipated"
>
<date>
  2009-12
</date>
</last_follow_up_date>
<primary_compl_date
 type="Anticipated"
>
<date>
  2009-04
</date>
</primary_compl_date>
<phase_block>
<phase>
  Phase 4
</phase>
</phase_block>
<study_type>
  Interventional
</study_type>
<design>
  Prevention
</design>
<design>
  Randomized
</design>
<design>
  Open Label
</design>
<design>
  Dose Comparison
</design>
<design>
  Parallel Assignment
</design>
<design>
  Safety/Efficacy Study
</design>
<number_of_arms>
  1
</number_of_arms>
<primary_outcome>
<measure>
  The primary objective of the study is to evaluate the efficacy of two dose levels of Naglazyme in preventing the progression of skeletal dysplasia in infants under the age of one year who have MPS VI
</measure>
<time_frame>
  One year after last patient is enrolled
</time_frame>
<safety_issue>
  No
</safety_issue>
</primary_outcome>
<enrollment
 type="Actual"
>
  4
</enrollment>
<condition>
  Mucopolysaccharidosis VI
</condition>
<condition>
  Maroteaux-Lamy Syndrome
</condition>
<intervention>
<intervent_type>
  Drug
</intervent_type>
<primary_name>
  galsulfase
</primary_name>
<description>
<textblock>
  Phase 4, multi-center, multi-national, open-label, randomized, two-dose level study.  Subjects randomized in a 1:1 fasion to receive weekly intravenous infusions of either 1.0 or 2.0 mg/kg of Naglazye for a minimum of 52 weeks or until the last patient enrolled has completed 52 weeks.
</textblock>
</description>
</intervention>
<eligibility>
<criteria>
<textblock>
  Inclusion Criteria:
    - Signed informed consent by a parent or legal guardian after the nature of the study has been explained and prior to any research-related procedures
 
    - Willing and able to comply with all study procedures
 
    - Equal to or greater than 36 weeks estimated gestational age by physical exam at birth
 
    - Has a diagnosis of MPS VI based on a documented prenatal diagnosis or fibroblast or leukocyte N-acetylgalactosamine 4-sulfatase (ASB) enzyme activity level of less than 10% of the lower limit of the normal range of the measuring laboratory
 
    - Is less than one year of age
 
    - Has no evidence of skeletal dysplasia based on physical exam
 
 
 
  Exclusion Criteria:
    - Perceived to be unreliable or unavailable for study participation or, if under the age of 18, have parents or legal guardians who are perceived to be unreliable or unavailable
 
    - Use of any investigational drug within 30 days prior to screening, or requirement for any investigational agent prior to completion of all scheduled study assessments
 
    - Concurrent disease or condition that would interfere with study participation or safety (i.e., has previously undergone hematopoietic stem cell transplantation such as bone marrow or cord blood transplantation, or major organ transplantation)
 
    - Any condition that, in the view of the PI, renders the subject at high risk from treatment compliance and/or completing the study
 
    - Has known hypersensitivity to Naglazyme
 
    - Has previously received Naglazyme
</textblock>
</criteria>
<healthy_volunteers>
  No
</healthy_volunteers>
<gender>
  Both
</gender>
<minimum_age>
</minimum_age>
<maximum_age>
  1 Years
</maximum_age>
</eligibility>
<investigator>
<role>
  Study Director
</role>
<name>
  Celeste Decker, MD
</name>
<affiliation>
<agency>
  BioMarin Pharmaceutical Inc
</agency>
</affiliation>
</investigator>
<contact>
<name>
  Linda A Scott, RN, BA
</name>
<phone>
  415-506-6700
</phone>
<phone_ext>
</phone_ext>
<email>
  lscott@bmrn.com
</email>
</contact>
<location>
<facility>
<name>
  Children&apos;s Hospital Oakland
</name>
<address>
<city>
  Oakland
</city>
<state>
  California
</state>
<zip>
  94609
</zip>
<country>
  United States
</country>
</address>
</facility>
<status>
Completed 
</status>
<contact>
<name>
  Paul Harmatz, M.D.
</name>
<phone>
</phone>
<phone_ext>
</phone_ext>
<email>
</email>
</contact>
</location>
<see_also>
<annotation>
<textblock>
  BioMarin Pharmaceutical Inc Website
</textblock>
</annotation>
<url>
  http://www.BRMN.com
</url>
</see_also>
<initial_release_date>
  2006-03-02
</initial_release_date>
<last_release_date>
2009-05-11 
</last_release_date>
<init_results_release_date>
</init_results_release_date>
</clinical_study>
