<clinical_study>
<study_id>
<org_name>
  Bayer
</org_name>
<org_full_name>
  Bayer Corporation
</org_full_name>
<org_study_id>
  100555
</org_study_id>
<nct_id>

</nct_id>
</study_id>
<brief_title>
<textblock>
  Evaluate the Best Overall Response Rate of BAY 43-9006 in Subjects with Metastatic Breast Cancer
</textblock>
</brief_title>
<official_title>
<textblock>
  A Phase II Multicenter Uncontrolled Trial of BAY 43-9006 in Subjects with Metastatic Breast Cancer
</textblock>
</official_title>
<study_sponsor>
<lead_sponsor>
<agency>
  Bayer Corporation
</agency>
</lead_sponsor>
</study_sponsor>
<oversight_info>
<regulatory_authority>
  United States: Food and Drug Administration
</regulatory_authority>
</oversight_info>
<brief_summary>
<textblock>
  The purpose of this multinational, multi-center, open label, uncontrolled, single arm phase II study is to assess the anti-tumor activity and safety profile of BAY 43-9006 as a single agent in subjects with metastatic breast cancer (MBC).  Subjects will be treated with BAY 43-9006 400 mg twice daily (b.i.d.) until there is objective evidence of tumor progression, evidence of toxicity that is unacceptable and thought to be related to study drug.
</textblock>
</brief_summary>
<detailed_descr>
<textblock>
</textblock>
</detailed_descr>
<status_block>
<status>
  No longer recruiting
</status>
<date>
  2005-01
</date>
</status_block>
<start_date>
<date>
</date>
</start_date>
<end_date>
<date>
</date>
</end_date>
<last_follow_up_date>
<date>
</date>
</last_follow_up_date>
<last_data_entry_date>
<date>
</date>
</last_data_entry_date>
<phase_block>
<phase>
  Phase 2
</phase>
</phase_block>
<study_type>
  Interventional
</study_type>
<design>
  Treatment
</design>
<design>
  Non-Randomized
</design>
<design>
  Open Label
</design>
<design>
  Uncontrolled
</design>
<design>
  Single Group Assignment
</design>
<design>
  Safety/Efficacy Study
</design>
<primary_outcome>
  To evaluate the best overall response rate, including complete response and partial response, of BAY 43-9006
</primary_outcome>
<secondary_outcome>
  Analyze time to disease progression
</secondary_outcome>
<secondary_outcome>
  Analyze time to response
</secondary_outcome>
<secondary_outcome>
  Anlayze duration of response
</secondary_outcome>
<secondary_outcome>
  Analyze survival time
</secondary_outcome>
<secondary_outcome>
  Evaluate rate of non-responders
</secondary_outcome>
<secondary_outcome>
  Evaluate quantitative and qualitative toxicity
</secondary_outcome>
<condition>
  Breast Cancer
</condition>
<condition>
  Metastases
</condition>
<intervention>
<intervent_type>
  Drug
</intervent_type>
<primary_name>
  BAY 43-9006, A Raf Kinase Inhibitor
</primary_name>
</intervention>
<eligibility>
<criteria>
<textblock>
  Inclusion Criteria:
    - Age &gt; 18 years
    - Women with prior histologically documented diagnosis of breast cancer
    - Subjects with metastatic disease who have already received and failed at least one chemotherapy regimen for metastatic disease and,
  if estrogen receptor/progesterone receptor positive (ER/PgR +ve), have failed on at least adjuvant hormonal therapy
    - Subjects for whom trastuzumab treatment is not indicated, no longer effective or refused by the subjects
    - Four weeks since the last cytotoxic chemotherapy or clear evidence of progression on hormonal therapy
    - Subjects who have at least one measurable lesion by CT scan or MRI
    - Subjects who have an Eastern Co-operative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0, 1 or 2
    - Adequate bone marrow, liver and renal function as assessed by the following laboratory requirements to be conducted within 7 days
  prior to screening: *Hemoglobin &gt; 9.0 g/dl, *Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &gt; 1,500/mm, *Platelet count &#8805;100,000/&#181;l, *Total bilirubin &#8804;1.5 x the upper limit of normal, *ALT and AST &#8804;2.5 x upper limit of normal (&#8804;5 x upper limit of
  normal for subjects with liver involvement of their cancer).
    - Amylase and lipase &#8804;1.5 x the upper limit of normal.
    - Serum creatinine &#8804;3.0 x the upper limit of normal.
    - PT or INR and PTT &lt; 1.5 x upper limit of normal (subjects who receive anti-coagulation treatment with an agent such as warfarin or heparin will be allowed to participate provided that no evidence of underlying abnormality in these parameters exists).
    - Subjects who give written informed consent prior to any study specific screening procedures with the understanding that the subject has the right to withdraw from the study at any time, without prejudice.
    - Life expectancy of at least 12 weeks
 
  Exclusion Criteria:
    - Previous malignancy (except for cervical carcinoma in situ, adequately treated basal cell carcinoma, or superficial bladder tumors [Ta, Tis and T1] or other malignancies curatively treated &gt; 2 years prior to entry)
    - Congestive heart failure &gt; NYHA Class II
    - Cardiac arrhythmia requiring anti-arrhythmic (excluding beta blockers or digoxin)
    - Active coronary artery disease or ischemia
    - Active clinically serious bacterial or fungal infections (&gt; grade 2 NCI-CTC, Version 3)
    - Known History of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection or chronic hepatitis B or C
    - Metastatic brain or meningeal tumors unless the subject is &gt; 6 months from definitive therapy, has a negative imaging study within 4 weeks of study entry and is clinically stable with respect to the tumor at the time of study entry. Also the patient must not be undergoing acute steroid therapy or taper (chronic steroid therapy is acceptable provided that the dose is stable for 1 month prior to and following screening radiographic study).
    - Subjects with seizure disorders requiring medication (such as steroid or anti-epileptics)
    - History of organ allograft
    - Substance abuse, medical, psychological or social conditions that may interfere with the subject&#8217;s participation in the study or evaluation of the study results
    - Known or suspected allergy to the investigational agent
    - Any condition that is unstable or which could jeopardize the safety of the subject and his/her compliance in the study
    - Pregnant or breast-feeding subjects. Women of childbearing potential must have a negative pregnancy test performed within seven days prior to the start of study drug. Women enrolled in this
  trial must use adequate barrier birth control measures during the course of the trial
</textblock>
</criteria>
<healthy_volunteers>
  No
</healthy_volunteers>
<patients>
</patients>
<expected_enrollment>
</expected_enrollment>
<gender>
  Female
</gender>
<minimum_age>
  18 Years
</minimum_age>
<maximum_age>
  N/A
</maximum_age>
</eligibility>
<contact>
<name>
  Clinical Communications
</name>
<phone>
  800-288-8371
</phone>
<phone_ext>
</phone_ext>
<email>
</email>
</contact>






</clinical_study>
