<clinical_study>
<study_id>
<org_name>
  WashingtonU
</org_name>
<org_full_name>
  Washington University School of Medicine
</org_full_name>
<org_study_id>
  201209088
</org_study_id>
<nct_id>
  NCT01661400
</nct_id>
</study_id>
<is_fda_regulated>
Yes 
</is_fda_regulated>
<is_section_801>
  No
</is_section_801>
<brief_title>
<textblock>
  Anti-Angiogenic Therapy Post Transplant (ASCR) for Relapsed and Refractory Pediatric Solid Tumors
</textblock>
</brief_title>
<acronym>
  ASCR
</acronym>
<official_title>
<textblock>
  Anti-Angiogenic Therapy After Autologous Stem Cell Rescue (ASCR) for Relapsed and Refractory Pediatric Solid Tumors
</textblock>
</official_title>
<study_sponsor>
<lead_sponsor>
<agency>
  Washington University School of Medicine
</agency>
</lead_sponsor>
</study_sponsor>
<resp_party>
<resp_party_type>
  Sponsor
</resp_party_type>
</resp_party>
<oversight_info>
<regulatory_authority>
  United States: Institutional Review Board
</regulatory_authority>
<has_dmc>
  No
</has_dmc>
</oversight_info>
<brief_summary>
<textblock>
  The purpose of this research study is to determine whether taking either of two low dose drugs that would prevent new blood vessels from growing after stem cell transplant is feasible, and what the side effects of taking each of these drugs after autologous transplant might be.  The reason the investigators are looking at these drugs is because one of the things that allows tumors to grow quickly is their ability to stimulate the growth of new blood vessels.  By suppressing the growth of new blood vessels after stem cell transplant, the investigators hope to prevent the tumors from coming back or continuing to grow.
</textblock>
</brief_summary>
<detailed_descr>
<textblock>
</textblock>
</detailed_descr>
<status_block>
<status>
 Recruiting 
</status>
<date>
2013-07 
</date>
</status_block>
<start_date>
<date>
2012-10 
</date>
</start_date>
<last_follow_up_date
 type="Anticipated"
>
<date>
  2020-02
</date>
</last_follow_up_date>
<primary_compl_date
 type="Anticipated"
>
<date>
  2015-02
</date>
</primary_compl_date>
<phase_block>
<phase>
 Phase 0 
</phase>
</phase_block>
<study_type>
  Interventional
</study_type>
<design>
  Treatment
</design>
<design>
  Non-Randomized
</design>
<design>
  Open Label
</design>
<design>
  Parallel Assignment
</design>
<design>
  Safety/Efficacy Study
</design>
<number_of_arms>
  3
</number_of_arms>
<primary_outcome>
<measure>
  Safety
</measure>
<time_frame>
 Minimum of 2 years after inititation of study treatment 
</time_frame>
<description>
<textblock>
Measured  by  absence  of  grade  4  or  5  non-hematological  or  grade  5  hematological  toxicity       
</textblock>
</description>
<safety_issue>
  Yes
</safety_issue>
</primary_outcome>
<primary_outcome>
<measure>
  Toxicity
</measure>
<time_frame>
 Minimum of 2 years after inititation of study treatment 
</time_frame>
<description>
<textblock>
  Measured by absence of grade 4 or 5 non-hematological or grade 5 hematological toxicity from baseline to Day +30
</textblock>
</description>
<safety_issue>
  Yes
</safety_issue>
</primary_outcome>
<secondary_outcome>
<measure>
  Radiographic marker of neovascularization
</measure>
<time_frame>
  86 days
</time_frame>
<description>
<textblock>
  Measurement of anti-angiogenic activity in the treatment of solid tumors from baseline to Day +86.
</textblock>
</description>
<safety_issue>
  No
</safety_issue>
</secondary_outcome>
<secondary_outcome>
<measure>
  Best overall response
</measure>
<time_frame>
  86 days
</time_frame>
<description>
<textblock>
  Assessed by Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) guideline version 1.1.
</textblock>
</description>
<safety_issue>
  No
</safety_issue>
</secondary_outcome>
<enrollment
 type="Anticipated"
>
12 
</enrollment>
<condition>
  Glioma
</condition>
<condition>
  Neuroectodermal Tumors, Primitive
</condition>
<condition>
  Wilms Tumor
</condition>
<condition>
  Rhabdomyosarcoma
</condition>
<condition>
  Sarcoma, Ewing
</condition>
<condition>
  Osteosarcoma
</condition>
<condition>
  Retinoblastoma
</condition>
<arm_group>
<arm_group_label>
  Control
</arm_group_label>
<arm_type>
 No Intervention 
</arm_type>
<description>
<textblock>
  No intervention
</textblock>
</description>
</arm_group>
<arm_group>
<arm_group_label>
  Metronomic Cyclophosphamide
</arm_group_label>
<arm_type>
  Experimental
</arm_type>
<description>
<textblock>
  Cyclophosphamide will be given PO once daily at 2.5 mg/kg/day for children &lt; 40kg or 100 mg daily for children &gt; 40kg beginning Day + 30 (30 days post transplant) and continue until at least Day +86
</textblock>
</description>
</arm_group>
<arm_group>
<arm_group_label>
  Thalidomide
</arm_group_label>
<arm_type>
  Experimental
</arm_type>
<description>
<textblock>
  Thalidomide will be initiated at 3mg/kg PO daily beginning Day + 30 (30 days post transplant) and continue until Day +86
</textblock>
</description>
</arm_group>
<intervention>
<intervent_type>
  Drug
</intervent_type>
<primary_name>
  Metronomic Cyclophosphamide
</primary_name>
<description>
<textblock>
</textblock>
</description>
<arm_group_label>
  Metronomic Cyclophosphamide
</arm_group_label>
<other_name>
  Cytoxan&#174;
</other_name>
<other_name>
  CPM
</other_name>
</intervention>
<intervention>
<intervent_type>
  Drug
</intervent_type>
<primary_name>
Thalidomide 
</primary_name>
<description>
<textblock>
</textblock>
</description>
<arm_group_label>
  Thalidomide
</arm_group_label>
<other_name>
  Thalomid&#174;
</other_name>
</intervention>
<eligibility>
<criteria>
<textblock>
  Inclusion Criteria:
 
  -Patient must have an original diagnosis confirmed by biopsy* of high-grade glial tumor, low-grade glial tumor, ependymoma, medulloblastoma, primitive neuro-ectodermal tumor (PNET), Wilms&apos; tumor, rhabdomyosarcoma, Ewing&apos;s sarcoma, osteosarcoma, retinoblastoma, or miscellaneous poor-prognosis solid tumors.  Lymphomas and other lymphoid malignancies will not be studied in this protocol.  
 
  * Brain stem glioma patients who have progressed after radiation therapy do not require histologic confirmation. Brain stem gliomas are defined as intrinsic tumors of the pons causing diffuse enlargement.  These patients are diagnosed on clinical and radiographic appearance of the lesion and the biopsy requirement will be waived for this group.
 
  -Patient must have pathologic or imaging confirmation of tumor progression or recurrence within 4 weeks prior to enrollment.
 
  -Patient must be &#8805; 5 years of age and &#8804; 21 years of age at the time of study entry.
 
  -Patient must have a Karnofsky performance status or Lansky* play status &#8805; 50   
 
  * For purpose of determining performance scores, wheelchair-bound patients will be considered ambulatory.
 
  -Patient must have an adequate supply of stem cells for transplant harvested prior to study enrollment, with adequate supply defined as 3 x 106 CD34+ cells/kg for peripheral blood stem cells (PBSC).  Cell mobilization method will be left up to the treating physician&apos;s discretion and may include mobilization growth factor alone or mobilization after chemotherapy.  If patient is unable to mobilize the proper amount of peripheral stem cells, bone marrow may be harvested as the source of hematopoietic stem cells.  In this instance, 3 x 108 mononuclear cells/kg will be considered adequate.  If necessary, a combination of peripheral stem cells and bone marrow can be used.
 
  -Prior radiation therapy and/or chemotherapy, including cyclophosphamide, are permitted.
 
  -Prior anti-angiogenic therapy, including thalidomide and oral cyclophosphamide, is permitted.
 
  -If on corticosteroids for mass effect and/or edema related to the tumor, patient must be on a stable dose for at least 2 weeks prior to study entry.
 
  -Patient must have a life expectancy &gt; 2 months. 
 
  -Patient must have an adequate bone marrow reserve as defined by:
*Hemoglobin &#8805;  9.0  g/dl  and  
*Platelet count  &#8805;  30,000/  mm3  (transfusion  independent)  and  
*Peripheral absolute  neutrophil  count  (ANC)  &#8805;  750/mm3  
 
  -Patient must have adequate cardiac function tested within 4 weeks of study enrollment as defined by:  
*Shortening fraction  of  &#8805;  27%  by  echocardiogram  or  
*Ejection fraction  of  &#8805;  50%  by  radionuclide  angiogram  
 
  -Patient must have adequate pulmonary function tested within 4 weeks of study enrollment as defined by:
*Pulse oximetry  &gt;  94%  on  room  air  or  O2  by  nasal  cannula  and  
*No evidence  of  dyspnea  at  rest.  
 
  -Patient must have adequate hepatic function as defined by:
*Total bilirubin  &#8804;  1.5x  upper  limit  of  normal  (ULN)  for  age  and  
*SGOT (AST)  or  SGPT  (ALT)  &#8804;  2.5  x  ULN  (SGOT  &#8804;  4x  ULN  if  on  Zantac)  
 
  -Patient must have adequate renal function as defined by:
*Serum creatinine  &lt;  1.5  mg/dl  
*Glomerular filtration  rate  (GFR),  calculated  via  I-125  iothalamate  clearance,  24-hour  creatinine  clearance,  or  Schwartz  formula*,  &#8805;  70  mL/min  and  &#8805;  50  mL/min/1.73  m2  done  within  4  weeks  of  study  entry  
 
  * The Schwartz formula is an estimated glomerular filtration rate in children based upon serum creatinine and height.  Height (Ht) should be measured in cm and serum creatinine (Cr) in mg/dL.  Proportionality constant (k) is 0.55 for children and adolescent girls and 0.7 for adolescent boys aged 13-21.  This constant is based upon a series of evaluations performed by Schwartz.   Formula:  GFR= (k x Ht)/Cr
 
  -If female of childbearing potential (defined as menstruating or amenorrheic from previous medical treatments), the following guidelines must be adhered to:
*If enrolled  in  Arm  III  of  this  study,  patient  must  be  registered  at  the  Celgene  S.T.E.P.S.  &#174;  Program.  
*If enrolled  in  Arm  III  of  this  study,  patient  must  be  willing  to  practice  birth  control  as  outlined  in  the  S.T.E.P.S.  Program  from  the  beginning  of  the  study  until  at  least  4  weeks  following  discontinuation  of  thalidomide  therapy.  Two  reliable  forms  of  contraception  must  be  used  simultaneously  unless  continuous  abstinence  from  heterosexual  sexual  contact  is  chosen.  Contraceptive  methods  must  include  at  least  one  highly  effective  method  (e.g.  oral  contraceptive  pills,  injections,  hormonal  patches,  IUD,  or  implants),  AND  one  additional  effective  barrier  method  (e.g.  latex  condom,  diaphragm,  cervical  cap).  If  hormonal  or  IUD  contraception  is  medically  contraindicated,  another  highly  effective  method  or  two  barrier  methods  must  be  used  at  the  same  time.  
  -Pregnancy surveillance:
*Patient must  have  a  negative  in  office  pregnancy  test  sensitive  to  within  50  mIU/mL  (serum  or  urine)  within  24  hours  of  beginning  thalidomide  even  if  continuous  abstinence  is  the  preferred  method  of  birth  control.  
*A pregnancy  test  must  be  performed  weekly  during  the  first  4  weeks  of  therapy  and  repeated  monthly  for  patients  with  regular  menses  or  every  2  weeks  for  patients  with  irregular  menses  
*Negative pregnancy  tests  are  valid  for  only  7  days.  
*If irregular  bleeding  or  skipped  menses,  pregnancy  test  should  be  performed  and  pregnancy  counseling  given.  
*If pregnancy  occurs  during  treatment,  thalidomide  must  be  immediately  discontinued.  Any  suspected  lethal  exposure  must  be  reported  immediately  to  Celgene  Customer  Care  Center  at  1-888-423-5346,  and  the  patient  referred  to  an  OB/GYN  experienced  in  reproductive  toxicity  for  further  evaluation  and  counseling.  
 
  -Patient (or legally authorized representative) must be able to understand and willing to sign a written informed consent document.
 
 
  Exclusion Criteria:
 
  -Patient must not have any active, uncontrolled cardiac, hepatic, renal, or psychiatric disease defined as &#8805; grade 3 based on NCI Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events v4.0 (CTCAE).
 
  -Patient must not be receiving any other investigational agents.
 
  -Patient must not have any active infection or concurrent illness obscuring toxicity or dangerously altering drug metabolism.
 
  -Patient must not have any thromboembolic event (deep vein thrombosis or pulmonary embolism) less than 3 weeks prior to enrollment.
 
  -Patient must not have a history of allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar chemical or biologic composition to any of the agents used in the study.
 
  -Patient must not be pregnant or breastfeeding.
 
  Inclusion of Women and Minorities 
 
  -Both men and women and members of all races and ethnic groups are eligible for this trial.
</textblock>
</criteria>
<healthy_volunteers>
  No
</healthy_volunteers>
<gender>
  Both
</gender>
<minimum_age>
  5 Years
</minimum_age>
<maximum_age>
  21 Years
</maximum_age>
</eligibility>
<investigator>
<role>
  Principal Investigator
</role>
<name>
  Lisa Madden, M.D.
</name>
<affiliation>
<agency>
  Washington University School of Medicine
</agency>
</affiliation>
</investigator>
<contact>
<name>
  Lisa Madden, M.D.
</name>
<phone>
  314-454-6018
</phone>
<phone_ext>
</phone_ext>
<email>
  madden_l@kids.wustl.edu
</email>
</contact>
<location>
<facility>
<name>
  Washington University School of Medicine
</name>
<address>
<city>
  St. Louis
</city>
<state>
  Missouri
</state>
<zip>
  63122
</zip>
<country>
  United States
</country>
</address>
</facility>
<status>
 Recruiting 
</status>
<contact>
<name>
  Lisa Madden, M.D.
</name>
<phone>
  314-454-6018
</phone>
<phone_ext>
</phone_ext>
<email>
  madden_l@kids.wustl.edu
</email>
</contact>
<contact>
<role>
  Sub-Investigator
</role>
<name>
  Robert Hayashi, M.D.
</name>
</contact>
<contact>
<role>
  Sub-Investigator
</role>
<name>
  Shalini Shenoy, M.D.
</name>
</contact>
<contact>
<role>
  Sub-Investigator
</role>
<name>
  Jeffrey Bednarski, M.D.
</name>
</contact>
<contact>
<role>
  Sub-Investigator
</role>
<name>
  Monica Hente, ARNP
</name>
</contact>
<contact>
<role>
  Sub-Investigator
</role>
<name>
  Geetika Khanna, M.D.
</name>
</contact>
<contact>
<role>
  Sub-Investigator
</role>
<name>
  Joshua Shimony, Ph.D.
</name>
</contact>
</location>
<see_also>
<annotation>
<textblock>
  Alvin J. Siteman Cancer Center at Barnes-Jewish Hospital and Washington University School of Medicine
</textblock>
</annotation>
<url>
  http://www.siteman.wustl.edu
</url>
</see_also>
<keyword>
  Glioma includes ependymoma and medulloblastoma
</keyword>
<initial_release_date>
  2012-07-30
</initial_release_date>
<last_release_date>
2013-07-29 
</last_release_date>
<init_disposition_release_date>
</init_disposition_release_date>
<init_results_release_date>
</init_results_release_date>
</clinical_study>
