<clinical_study>
<study_id>
<org_name>
  UAarhus
</org_name>
<org_full_name>
  University of Aarhus
</org_full_name>
<org_study_id>
  20050213
</org_study_id>
<secondary_id>
  20050213 - 19/04-2006
</secondary_id>
<nct_id>
  NCT00362401
</nct_id>
</study_id>
<brief_title>
<textblock>
Patients  Perception  of  Mechanical  Heart  Valve  Sounds:  Psychoacoustics  and  Quality  of Life  
</textblock>
</brief_title>
<official_title>
<textblock>
Patients  Perception  of  Mechanical  Heart  Valve  Sounds:  Psychoacoustics  and  Quality  of Life  
</textblock>
</official_title>
<study_sponsor>
<lead_sponsor>
<agency>
  University of Aarhus
</agency>
</lead_sponsor>
<sponsor>
<agency>
  Herz- und Diabeteszentrum Nordrhein Westfalen
</agency>
</sponsor>
</study_sponsor>
<oversight_info>
<regulatory_authority>
  Denmark: Ethics Committee
</regulatory_authority>
</oversight_info>
<brief_summary>
<textblock>
  The purpose of this study is to assess the influence of the perceived sound from different types of mechanical heart valves in patient&#180;s quality of life different times after the valve implantation
</textblock>
</brief_summary>
<detailed_descr>
<textblock>
  Patient&#8217;s perception of mechanical heart valve sounds: psychoacoustics and quality of life
 
  Background: Approximately 90.000 mechanical prosthetic heart valves are implanted every year all over the world. They generate a clicking sound at closure, which can be a major problem for some patients. About 12% of them all experience annoyance, concentration disturbance, sleeping disorders and social embarrassment. All those factors could affect patients&#8217; quality of life. The conduction of this sound occurs externally (through the air) and internally (through bones and vessels). The internal-transmitted vibrations make the perception for the patient two to four times higher than the air-transmitted route alone. The displeasure caused by those sounds is analyzed in the context of psychoacoustics. The psychoacoustic parameters provide a very precise appraise of the perceived annoyance instead of physical parameters (such as loudness) only. Regarding annoyance related to mechanical heart valves sound, some aspects still remain to be examined, such as those described in our hypotheses. 
 
  Hypotheses: A) Different mechanical heart valves produce different degree of annoyance for patients. 
  B) There is a direct relationship between the patients&#8217; perception of the sound produced by their valves (psychoacoustic annoyance) and the impairment in their quality of life. 
  C) The annoyance from mechanical heart valve sounds decreases with time.
 
  Aims: To analyze whether the annoyance from a mechanical heart valve sound is related to the type of valve which is implanted; To assess the impact of annoyance from mechanical heart valve sound on patients quality of life different times after their implantation. 
 
  Material and Methods: There will be included 150 patients with an implanted mechanical heart valve (ATS Medical, Medtronic-Hall or St. Jude Medical) in the aortic position between 3 months and 4&#189; years before the analysis. The externally, internally and total perceived valve sound will be measured (by a method designed by the authors) for each patient and the psychoacoustic annoyance will be calculated. The measures will take place in a bioacoustical laboratory built with a sound-insulated chamber with a very low background noise, designed for the purposes of the study. Those measures will be performed in German patients followed by &#8220;The Heart Centre&#8221; in Bad Oeynhausen (Herz- und Diabeteszentrum Nordrhein Westfalen, University of Bochum), where the mentioned laboratory is constructed. The externally conducted sound (SPL1) will be measured by a microphone placed close to the patient&#8217;s ear, which records and sends the sound to a PC-program, capable to analyze the different parameters which compose a sound vibration. The total transmitted sound (externally + internally) is measured through a &#8220;biofeedback procedure&#8221;, where the resulting sound from the SLP1 is played back to the patient through a loudspeaker. The patient then has to adjust (by a remote control) the amplitude of the played sound to a level equal to the total perceived sound. After that, the microphone next to the patient&#8217;s ear records both the directly air-transmitted sound from the valve (SPL1) and the feedback sound from the speaker, adjusted by the patient. By this, we include both the air-transmitted and the bone-transmitted vibrations to the final feedback sound (SPL3). The internally conducted sound (SPL2) is estimated by subtracting the total transmitted sound from the air-transmitted sound. Subsequently, the psychoacoustic annoyance can be calculated through a specific formula, which includes different sound parameters. The scoring program SF-36 plus specific questions regarding complaints from mechanical heart valve sounds will be used in order to test whether there is a relation between the patients&#8217; perception of their valve sound and the impairment in their quality of life. In order to test the last hypothesis, additionally 50 recently operated patients (one- to three months before the analysis) will be submitted twice to the above mentioned measures within a 2 years interval, in order to establish whether there is a time-dependant factor in the annoyance caused by the valve sound. This side-study will be performed with Danish patients, all operated at the &#8220;Skejby Sygehus&#8221;, &#197;rhus University Hospital, in a corresponding bioacoustical laboratory built at this institution.
 
 
  Perspectives: The results obtained from this analysis will contribute to expand knowledge concerning psychoacoustics and its influence on quality of life &#8211; a subject with lack of understanding. The study can add one important parameter in the choice of the implanted valve: patient&#8217;s pleasantness. It will assess some of the most sold mechanical heart valve worldwide and the final results can contribute to elucidate which type, among those valves, that should be chosen to a specific patient.
</textblock>
</detailed_descr>
<status_block>
<status>
  Recruiting
</status>
<date>
  2006-08
</date>
</status_block>
<start_date>
<date>
  2005-11
</date>
</start_date>
<end_date>
<date>
  2009-12
</date>
</end_date>
<last_follow_up_date>
<date>
  2006-04
</date>
</last_follow_up_date>
<last_data_entry_date>
<date>
  2007-02
</date>
</last_data_entry_date>
<phase_block>
<phase>
  Phase 0
</phase>
</phase_block>
<study_type>
  Observational
</study_type>
<design>
  Psychosocial
</design>
<design>
  Longitudinal
</design>
<design>
  Defined Population
</design>
<design>
  Retrospective Study
</design>
<condition>
  Heart Valve Diseases
</condition>
<eligibility>
<criteria>
<textblock>
  Inclusion Criteria:
    - Adult patients (18 years of age and older), who have acquired an aortic mechanical heart valve, which belongs to one of the three investigated valve types and have been implanted from three months to four years before the investigation.
 
  Exclusion Criteria:
    - Patients with severe hearing impairment (evaluated by a conventional audiogram inside the sound-insulated chamber) or who use hearing aid; patients with severe cardiac arrhythmias; patients with claustrophobia; patients who are not capable of cooperating to the experimental conditions at a sound-insulated chamber; patients who are unable to fulfil the quality of life questionnaire.
</textblock>
</criteria>
<healthy_volunteers>
  No
</healthy_volunteers>
<patients>
</patients>
<expected_enrollment>
  200
</expected_enrollment>
<gender>
  Both
</gender>
<minimum_age>
  18 Years
</minimum_age>
<maximum_age>
  N/A
</maximum_age>
</eligibility>
<investigator>
<role>
  Principal Investigator
</role>
<name>
  Thais A. Pedersen, doctor
</name>
<affiliation>
<agency>
  Aarhus University
</agency>
</affiliation>
</investigator>
<contact>
<name>
  Thais A. Pedersen, doctor
</name>
<phone>
  +45 89495480
</phone>
<phone_ext>
</phone_ext>
<email>
  thais.a.pedersen@ki.au.dk
</email>
</contact>
<contact>
<name>
  Michael Hasenkam, Professor
</name>
<phone>
  +45 89495481
</phone>
<phone_ext>
</phone_ext>
<email>
  hasenkam@ki.au.dk
</email>
</contact>
<location>
<facility>
<name>
  Herz- und Diabeteszentrum Nordrhein Westfalen
</name>
<address>
<city>
  Bad Oeynhausen
</city>
<state>
</state>
<zip>
  32545
</zip>
<country>
  Germany
</country>
</address>
</facility>
<status>
  Recruiting
</status>
<contact>
<name>
  Heinrich K&#246;rtke, doctor
</name>
<phone>
  49 ( 5731 ) 970 -
</phone>
<phone_ext>
</phone_ext>
<email>
  herzchirurgie@hdz-nrw.de
</email>
</contact>
<contact>
<role>
  Principal Investigator
</role>
<name>
  Thais A. Pedersen, doctor
</name>
</contact>
</location>
<location>
<facility>
<name>
  Herz- und Diabeteszentrum Nordrhein Westfalen
</name>
<address>
<city>
  Bad Oeynhausen
</city>
<state>
</state>
<zip>
  32545
</zip>
<country>
  Germany
</country>
</address>
</facility>
<status>
  Recruiting
</status>
<contact>
<name>
  Heinrich K&#246;rtke, doctor
</name>
<phone>
  49 ( 5731 ) 970 -
</phone>
<phone_ext>
</phone_ext>
<email>
  herzchirurgie@hdz-nrw.de
</email>
</contact>
<contact>
<role>
  Principal Investigator
</role>
<name>
  Thais A. Pedersen, doctor
</name>
</contact>
</location>
<keyword>
  Psychoacoustics
</keyword>
<keyword>
  Quality of Life
</keyword>
<keyword>
  Heart Valve Prosthesis
</keyword>
<initial_release_date>
  2006-08-09
</initial_release_date>
<last_release_date>
2006-08-10 
</last_release_date>
</clinical_study>
