<clinical_study>
<study_id>
<org_name>
FreseniusKD 
</org_name>
<org_full_name>
 Fresenius  Kabi    
</org_full_name>
<org_study_id>
  BFP502
</org_study_id>
<nct_id>
  NCT00308100
</nct_id>
</study_id>
<is_fda_regulated>
  No
</is_fda_regulated>
<brief_title>
<textblock>
  Hydroxyethyl Starch (130/0.4) for Intravascular Volume Therapy in Liver Transplantation
</textblock>
</brief_title>
<official_title>
<textblock>
  A Multicenter, Randomized, Open-Label, Parallel-Group, Albumin-Controlled Phase IV Study to Evaluate the Efficacy and Safety of Hydroxyethyl Starch (130/0.4) for Intravascular Volume Therapy in Patients Undergoing Liver Transplantation
</textblock>
</official_title>
<study_sponsor>
<lead_sponsor>
<agency>
 Fresenius  Kabi    
</agency>
</lead_sponsor>
</study_sponsor>
<resp_party>
<name_title>
  Professor Leng Xisheng
</name_title>
<organization>
  Beijing Renmin Hospital
</organization>
</resp_party>
<oversight_info>
<regulatory_authority>
  China: State Food and Drug Administration
</regulatory_authority>
<has_dmc>
  Yes
</has_dmc>
</oversight_info>
<brief_summary>
<textblock>
  There are no standardized plasma volume replacement protocols during liver transplantation surgery. The current study is designed to compare efficacy, safety, and costs of perioperative volume replacement with Voluven (Hydroxyethyl starch 130/0.4) and albumin in patients undergoing liver transplantation.
</textblock>
</brief_summary>
<detailed_descr>
<textblock>
End-stage  liver  disease  is  one  of  the  major  diseases  leading  to  death.  With  advancement  of  transplantation  surgery  and  perioperative  anesthesia  management,  liver  transplantation  has  become  an  effective  method  to  recover  patients&apos; liver  function,  thus  saving  their  lives  and  improving  their  quality  of  life.  Serious  disorders  of  fluid  balance,  such  as  blood  coagulation  dysfunction,  electrolyte  disequilibrium,  hypoalbuminaemia,  low  hematocrit,  low  hemoglobin  and  acid-base  imbalance  etc.  exist  in  end  stage  cirrhosis  patients  with  liver  transplantation.  Such  abnormalities  in  the  internal  milieu  could  cause  or  worsen  cardiovascular  and  pulmonary  dysfunction,  thus  making  perioperative  management  more  difficult.  
 
  Albumin and blood plasma are conventionally used as plasma volume expanders in clinical practice. At the same time, the level of albumin concentration is also used as an important criterion of prognosis. When the level of albumin concentration in serum is below 35 g/L, postoperative mortality rates and complications will increase significantly. In fact, it has been the focus of debate for many years whether albumin should be used for volume replacement in critically ill patients. Boldt and his colleagues demonstrated that albumin has little positive influence on the prognosis of critically ill patients. However, Shwe deemed albumin beneficial to critically ill patients. Simon suggested that albumin is given mainly for treating hypovolemia instead of increasing the level of albumin concentration in serum. However, at the same time, he admitted there is no advantages of albumin in comparison to other colloid solutions and, furthermore, it is more expensive.
 
 
  Voluven (130/0.4) is a medium molecular weight hydroxyethyl starch (HES) produced by Beijing Fresenius Kabi Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd. It is a novel HES preparation with optimized molecular weight and molecule distribution, has a lower degree of substitution (DS) (0.4), and a narrower molecular distribution profile (C2/C6) than other available HES specifications which make it more suitable for volume replacement therapy. Some studies have revealed that Voluven (130/0.4) has a comparable efficacy with HAES-steril (average molecular weight 200.000 dalton, degree of substitution 0.5). Because of its improved pharmacological profile, Voluven (130/0.4) is used to avoid capillary vessel leakage and improve oxygenation of tissues. In addition, Voluven (130/0.4) does not accumulate in plasma or tissues even after multiple dosing (maximal dose 50 ml/kg), and has an improved HES safety profile in terms of coagulation and kidney function. 
 
  The current study is designed to assess the efficacy, safety, and pharmaceutical economics characteristic of perioperative volume replacement with Voluven (130/0.4) in patients undergoing liver transplantation compared with patients who received volume therapy with albumin. The objective of this study is to supply appropriate regimens for patients undergoing liver transplantation, considering clinical efficacy, safety, and costs.
</textblock>
</detailed_descr>
<status_block>
<status>
 Active, not recruiting 
</status>
<date>
2008-04 
</date>
</status_block>
<start_date>
<date>
  2005-10
</date>
</start_date>
<end_date>
<date>
  2006-10
</date>
</end_date>
<last_follow_up_date
 type="Anticipated"
>
<date>
  2008-08
</date>
</last_follow_up_date>
<primary_compl_date
 type="Anticipated"
>
<date>
  2008-04
</date>
</primary_compl_date>
<phase_block>
<phase>
  Phase 4
</phase>
</phase_block>
<study_type>
  Interventional
</study_type>
<design>
  Treatment
</design>
<design>
  Randomized
</design>
<design>
  Open Label
</design>
<design>
  Active Control
</design>
<design>
  Parallel Assignment
</design>
<design>
  Safety/Efficacy Study
</design>
<number_of_arms>
  2
</number_of_arms>
<primary_outcome>
<measure>
  Hemodynamics
</measure>
<time_frame>
  From pre-operative period till discharged from hospital
</time_frame>
<safety_issue>
  No
</safety_issue>
</primary_outcome>
<secondary_outcome>
<measure>
  Child-Turcotte-Pugh (CTP) score
</measure>
<time_frame>
  From pre-operative period till discharged from hospital
</time_frame>
<safety_issue>
  No
</safety_issue>
</secondary_outcome>
<secondary_outcome>
<measure>
  Model for End-Stage Liver Disease (MELD) score
</measure>
<time_frame>
  From pre-operative period till discharged from hospital
</time_frame>
<safety_issue>
  No
</safety_issue>
</secondary_outcome>
<enrollment
 type="Anticipated"
>
  200
</enrollment>
<condition>
  Intraoperative Complications
</condition>
<arm_group>
<arm_group_label>
  1
</arm_group_label>
<arm_type>
  Experimental
</arm_type>
<description>
<textblock>
</textblock>
</description>
</arm_group>
<arm_group>
<arm_group_label>
  2
</arm_group_label>
<arm_type>
  Active Comparator
</arm_type>
<description>
<textblock>
</textblock>
</description>
</arm_group>
<intervention>
<intervent_type>
  Drug
</intervent_type>
<primary_name>
  Hydroxyethylstarch 130/0.4
</primary_name>
<description>
<textblock>
  HES 130/0.4, administered intra- and perioperatively, max. daily dose: 33ml/kg BW; if needed, additionally albumin is administered (ratio crystalloid to colloid= 1:1)
</textblock>
</description>
<arm_group_label>
  1
</arm_group_label>
<other_name>
  HES 130/0.4
</other_name>
<other_name>
  Hydroxyethyl starch 130/0.4
</other_name>
</intervention>
<intervention>
<intervent_type>
  Drug
</intervent_type>
<primary_name>
 5% Albumin 
</primary_name>
<description>
<textblock>
  5% albumin, administered intra- and perioperatively
</textblock>
</description>
<arm_group_label>
  2
</arm_group_label>
</intervention>
<eligibility>
<criteria>
<textblock>
  Inclusion Criteria:
    - Aged 18-65 years, male or female
    - Elective liver transplantation
    - United Network for Organ Sharing (UNOS) Level 2A/B or 3         
    - Serum albumin &#8805; 30 g/L
    - Comprehend all the procedures of this study 
    - Willing and able to give informed consent
 
 
  Exclusion Criteria:
    -  Uncontrolled exo-hepatic malignant carcinomas
    -  Uncontrollable infections (including HIV infection)
    -  Need support of artificial liver or kidney, ventilator-dependant, coma or    unstable hemodynamically
    - Patients with a history of hypersensitivity to hydroxyethyl starch or albumin
    -  Urinary output less than 500 ml within 24 hours after operation
    -  Patients with intracranial bleeding
    -  Patients with other colloids for treating hypovolemia
    -  Patients with pulmonary edema
    -  Pregnant women or females of childbearing potential and lactating mothers
    -  Patients who are participating in other drug studies or who receive other investigational drugs within 30 days prior to the present study
</textblock>
</criteria>
<healthy_volunteers>
  No
</healthy_volunteers>
<gender>
  Both
</gender>
<minimum_age>
  18 Years
</minimum_age>
<maximum_age>
  65 Years
</maximum_age>
</eligibility>
<investigator>
<role>
  Principal Investigator
</role>
<name>
  Xisheng Leng, MD
</name>
<affiliation>
<agency>
  People&apos;s University of Peking University
</agency>
</affiliation>
</investigator>
<contact>
<name>
  Fengxue Zhu, MD
</name>
<phone>
  13911005275
</phone>
<phone_ext>
</phone_ext>
<email>
</email>
</contact>
<location>
<facility>
<name>
  People&apos;s Hospital of Peking University
</name>
<address>
<city>
  Beijing
</city>
<state>
</state>
<zip>
  100044
</zip>
<country>
  China
</country>
</address>
</facility>
<status>
 Active, not recruiting 
</status>
<contact>
<role>
  Sub-Investigator
</role>
<name>
  Fengxue Zhu, MD
</name>
</contact>
</location>
<keyword>
  Liver Transplantation
</keyword>
<initial_release_date>
  2006-03-28
</initial_release_date>
<last_release_date>
2008-04-29 
</last_release_date>
</clinical_study>
